Guide to the Caroline Farrar Ware (UNESCO) Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets and books (Box 28–34)
    - Material on international labor organizations
      - Saposs, David. Labor in Western Europe. University of California, Institute of Industrial Relations. Berkeley, 1955 (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Huxley, Julian. Evolutionary Humanism. Australian Institute of International Affairs. Melbourne, Australia, 1954 (Box 34)
      - Belgian Congo Government Council. Speech by the Governor General, M. L. P é tillon, 1955 (Box 34)
      - Staley, Eugene. The American Citizen's Stake in the Progress of Less Developed Areas of the World. Prepared for the United States National Commission for Unesco. California, Stanford Research Institute, June 1954 (Box 34)
      - Agriculture in Britain. London, Cetral Office of Information, 1955 (Box 34)
      - Political and Economic Planning. The British Film Industry: A Report by PEP. London, 1952 (Box 34)
    - Egypt
      - Ministry of Education. Educational Progress throughout the Scholastic Year, 1955 (Box 28)
      - Ministry of Education. Guiding Principles for Secondary School Teachers. Cairo, 1955 (Box 28)
      - The Permanent Council for Public Welfare Services. Cairo, July 1955 (Box 28)
      - The Egyptian Gazette (announcing new constitution for Egypt), January 17, 1956 (Box 28)
      - Egypt: The Youngest Republic in the World, 6000 Years Old. Washington, D.C., Egyptian Embassy, 1954 (Box 28)
      - The Coptic Church: Christianity in Egypt. Washington, D.C., s.d. (Box 28)
      - Nasser, Gamal Abdel. "The Egyptian Revolution." Reprinted from Foreign Affairs, January 1955 (Box 28)
      - Nasser, Gamal Abd el-. The Philosophy of the Revolution, Book I. Cairo, s.d. (Box 28)
      - Hussein, Mme Ahmed. Women in the Moslem World. Washington, D.C., Egyptian Embassy, 1954 (Box 28)
    - Ethiopia (Box 29)
      - This is Ethiopia: 1930-1955, November 1955 (Box 29)
      - This is Ethiopia, Spring 1958 (Box 29)
      - This is Ethiopia, Summer 1958 (Box 29)
      - Rivers of Ethiopia (Box 29)
    - Indonesia
      - Heeren, H. J. The Urbanization of Djakarta (mimeo), undated (Box 29)
      - The Indonesian Women's Congress (mimeo) (Box 29)
      - van Leur, J. C. Indonesian Trade and Society: Essays in Asian Social and Economic History. The Hague, W. van Hoeve Ltd, 1955 (Box 28)
    - Japan
      - Ministry of Labor. Statistical Materials Relating to Japanese Women. No. 7, July 1955 (Box 29)
      - Japanese National Commission for Unesco. Unesco Activities in Japan, December 1953 (Box 29)
      - Kunio Odaka. Japanese Sociology: Past and Present (mimeo). Tokyo University, October 1949 (Box 29)
      - The Daily Labor Press, Inc. The Labor Union Movement in Postwar Japan. Tokyo, 1954 (Box 29)
      - Japan Sociological Society (Box 29)
        - A Selected Bibliography concerning Social Stratification and Mobility in Japan since 1800 (mimeo), April 1953 (Box 29)
        - Report of a Sample Survey of Social Stratification and Mobility in Six Large Cities of Japan (mimeo), December 1954 (Box 29)
        - Proposal for Further Inquiries into Social Stratification and Social Mobility in Japan (mimeo), 1955 (Box 29)
      - Schoolhouses in Japan. Tokyo, The Perfect 6-3 Educational System, s.d. (Box 29)
      - Minstry of Education. Education in Japan: A Graphic Presentation. Tokyo, August 1954 (Box 29)
      - Motion Picture Association of Japan. Japanese Motion Picture Industry, 1955 (Box 29)
      - Eijiro Honjo. The Social and Economic History of Japan. Kyoto, Institute for Research in Economic History of Japan, 1935 (Box 28)
      - The Keizai Orai, No. 12 (in Japanese) (Box 28)
      - Collection of theWorld Arts (in Japanese). Japan (Modern) IV and Japan (Modern) V. Tokyo, Heibonsha, 1954 (Box 29)
      - Brief History of Modern Japan (in Japanese, 2 volumes). Compiled by Todoa Yauchibara. Tokyo, Misuzu Shaba, 1953 (Box 28)
      - Housewives Holding a Pencil (in Japanese). Compiled by Kazuko Tsurumi. Tokyo, Mainichi, 1954 (Box 28)
      - History of my Mother (in Japanese). Compiled by Junji Kinoshita and Kazuko Tsurumi. Tokyo, Kowaide, 1955 (Box 28)
      - Eijiro Honjo
        - A Bibliography of Japanese Economic history, 1796-1935 (pamphlet). Kyoto, Nihon Keizaishi Kenkyusho, 1936 (Box 29)
        - "Economic Ideas in Tokugawa Days." Reprint from Kyoto Univ. Economic Review, Vol. 13, #1 (Box 29)
        - "Die vorkapitalistische Periode in der Entwicklung der Japanishchen Volkswirtschaft." Reprint from Weltsirtscharflishes Archiv, Juli 1937, Jena (Box 29)
      - Smaller Enterprise Agency, Ministry of International Trade and Industry. Present Aspects of Smaller Enterprise in Japan and its Problems (pamphlet), May 1953 (Box 29)
    - Burma
      - Ministry of Information. Burma: A Handbook, 1954 (Box 29)
      - Mass Education: Burma (Box 29)
      - The Directory of Social Welfare Agencies and Organizations: Burma, 1954 (Box 29)
      - Ministry of Education. Educational Plan for a Welfare State, 1952 (Box 29)
      - Education in Burma: before Independence and after Independence, 1953 (Box 29)
      - Burma Translation Society, What it is, What it does (Box 29)
    - Thailand
      - Questionnaire on the Legal Status and Treatment of Women and Answers of the Government of Thailand, 1954 (Box 29)
      - Mme Pibulsonggram. Thai Women (Box 29)
      - Thailand Women's Association. Club News, 1954-1955 (Box 29)
      - Prince Dhani Nivat. "The Reconstruction of Rama I of the Chakri Dynasty." Reprint from Journal of the Siam Society, August 1955 (Box 29)
    - Iran
      - Iran Today, Vol. I, No. 2 (Box 29)
      - Iran. Iran Information Center (Box 29)
      - Hakmat, A. A. Social Organization of Iran (mimeo). New Delhi, January 1956 (Box 29)
    - Iraq
      - Ministry of Education, Regulations of the Iran Academy for the year 1947, 1949 (Box 29)
      - Higher Teachers' College Bulletin. Baghdad, 1951-1955 (Box 29)
      - Academic Review of the Higher Teachers' College, Vol. IV, No. 1. Baghdad, 1955 (Box 29)
    - Afghanistan
      - Afghanistan: Development in Brief (Box 29)
      - Afghanistan Review, Vol. I, No. 1, November 1958 (Box 29)
    - Morocco
      - Education in Morocco (mimeo), 1959 (Box 29)
      - Mohammed V, King of Morocco. Rabat, 1957 (Box 29)
      - The New Government of Morocco. Washington, D.C., Embassy of Morocco, May 1958 (Box 29)
      - Morocco 1957: Visit of His Majesty Mohammed V to the U.N. (Box 29)
    - Malaysia
      - Social Services in the Federation of Malaya. London, Central Office of Information, 1954 (Box 28)
      - Social Welfare Department, Singapore. Annual Report for 1954 (Box 28)
      - Cook, Gertrude. The Work of the Social Welfare Department, Singapore. (mimeo), April 1955 (Box 28)
      - Gamba, Charles. Labor Law in Malaya (pamphlet). Singapore, 1955 (Box 28)
      - Goh Keng Swee. Urban Incomes & Housing: Rept. On Social Survey of Singapore 1953-1956 (Box 28)
    - Poland
      - Lorentz, Stanislaw. Museums and Collections in Poland, 1945-1955. Warsaw, Polonia Publishing House, 1956 (Box 28)
      - Zachwatowicz, Jan. Protection of Historical Monuments in People's Poland. Warsaw, Polonia Publishing House, 1956 (Box 28)
      - Ten Years of People's Poland. August Grodzicki, Theatre; Irena Marz, Film. Warsaw, Polonia Publishing House, 1955 (Box 28)
      - Marek, Tadeusz. La Musique Polonaise Contemporaine 1945-1956. Varsovie, Editions "Polonia", 1957 (Box 28)
      - An Exhibition of Polish Posters, s.d. (Box 28)
      - An Exhibition of Contemporary Polish Photography, s.d. (Box 28)
- Additional Material, Accession 1991-M-036
  Addition inventory by Carol King, July 1990
  Received from: Estate of Caroline M. Ware: E. A. Prichard, Robert and Helen Barnard, executors. August 22, 1990
  .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  - Correspondence and subject files
    - George Allen and Unwin Ltd., 1963-1967 (Box 1)
    - Métraux, Guy S., 1967, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Panikkar, K. M., 1958-1963 (Box 1)
    - Romein, Jan M., 1955-1958, 1962-1970 (Box 1)
    - History of Mankind, 1969
      - Vol. VI Tome 2, 1962-1965 (Box 2)
      - Translation into languages other than English, 1954-1956, 1962 (Box 2)
      - Reactive file, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
      - Distribution, 1966-1968 (Box 2)
      - Discarded material, 1954-1958 (Box 2)
    - Publicity and reviews, 1954-1972 (Box 2)
    - World History Association, 1986-1987, undated (Box 2)
    - Draft of Three Across the World, by Caroline F. Ware, undated (Box 2)
    - Draft of Writing World History with an International Team, by Caroline F. Ware: previously entitled Three Across the World, undated
      - Correspondence pertaining to Writing World History, 1965-1968 (Box 2)